PERSONAL INFORMATION Sh



Shah Nawaz

- House # 64, Block # 5, Sector C-2, Township, Lahore (Pakistan)
- (+92) 333-6559448, (+92) 300-9228998

Gender Male | Date of birth 15/02/1980 | Nationality Pakistani

Domicile Faisalabad | Religion Islam | Marital status Married

Currently serving University of Gujrat, Lahore Sub Campus as Head of the Department/ Lecturer, Department of Software Engineering. Prior to this served Educational Research projects [PEAS/PEC] funded by The World Bank under Govt. of the Punjab, Education Department as Computer Programmer/Head of IT Section (BS-17) for more than 08 years and Deputy Director (Admin) for 02 years.

SUMMARY

Gained expertise as Lecturer, Head of the Department, Academic Coordinator, Resource Person/Teacher Trainer, design/conduct capacity building/training workshops and educational material development. Worked with foreign consultants and teams of The World Bank, UNICEF, Mickensy, ACER, Cambridge Education, Chief Minister Road Map Team, GIZ, Danish Schools of Excellence, PITB, QAED, PTB, PEAS and PEC for quality of educational research & development.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

22/05/2019

M.S. (Computer Science)

Riphah International University, Islamabad, (Pakistan)

30/09/2003

Masters of Computer Sciences (MCS)

Imperial College of Business Studies (ICBS), Lahore (Pakistan)

05/07/2000

Bachelor of Computer Sciences (BCS)

Al-Khair University, AJK (Pakistan)

24/12/2008

IELTS – 6.0 band [7.0 in spoken module]

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Total = 13+ years [8 years Govt. of the Punjab & 4 years Private sector]

15/11/2015- Present

Head of the Department (Department of SE) Fall 2016 to Till Now Lecturer (Dept. of Software Engineering)

Project Management Officer (PMO) Advisor, Software Engineering Society

University of Gujrat Lahore Sub Campus, Lahore (Pakistan)

10/06/2006 - 08/01/2015

Computer Programmer/ Head of IT Section (BPS-17)

Teacher Trainer/Resource Person

Govt. of the Punjab, Education Department, Lahore (Pakistan)

- Punjab Examination Commission (PEC)
- Punjab Education Assessment System (PEAS)

24/05/2013 - 08/03/2014

Deputy Director (Admn) (BS-18), [Additional Charge]

Govt. of the Punjab, Education Department, Lahore (Pakistan)

Punjab Education Assessment System (PEAS)

AREAS OF EXPERTIES

- Teaching
- Academic Administration
- Teacher Trainer /IT resource person
- Curriculum development
- Design & Impart Trainings, capacity building workshops
- Report writing, Article Writing, Book Writing, Training Manuals, Training Guides
- Concept Note / Action Plan/ PC-1 Development

INTERNATIONAL RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS:

2011 - How to Assess Students' Learning

Journal: The International Journal of Science in Society [C.G. Publisher],

2014 University of Illinois, USA

- Object Oriented Incremental Process Model for Data Warehouse Implementation

Journal: The International Journal of Science in Society [C.G. Publisher], University of Illinois, USA

- Vision on Effective Aid & Development

Journal: Academic Research International (AR Int.), Pakistan

TRAININGS CONDUCTED:

2011

Designed & Conducted Trainings on

2014 - Online Student Registration System of PEC

Punjab Examination Commission, Govt. of the Punjab, Lahore

2014 - Induction Training of Subject Specialists on IT and lesson planning

Quaide Azam Academy of Education Development (QAED), Govt. of the Punjab, Lhr

2012 - Training of Head Teachers on Computer Sciences/ICT - 2012

Quaide Azam Academy of Education Development (QAED), Govt. of the Punjab, Lhr

2014 - Computer Science tutor - (Registration # 12-PLE-T0509)

Allama Iqbal Open University (AIOU)

TRAININGS RECEIEVED: - In-country training on Sampling for research- March 2008 Mar 2008 Organized by: The World Bank Institute, Islamabad - Training Workshop on Educational Management Information System (EMIS) Jun 2006 The World Bank Institute Islamabad, National Education Assessment System [NEAS], MoE, Policy & Planning Wing Islamabad Dec 2012 - Training Workshop for Test Item Writers Organized by: Cambridge Education, MM Pakistan (Pvt) Ltd. & Australian Council for Educational Research [ACER], Australia Nov 2011 - Workshop on the Adoption of Curriculum Implementation Framework, GIZ, Lahore Mar 2008 - Workshop on Background Data Analysis for 2006 National Assessment The World Bank Institute Islamabad, National Education Assessment System [NEAS], Ministry of Education, Policy & Planning Wing Islamabad - Workshop on TQM, Six Sigma and Outcome Based Education (OBE) July 2016 By: Farrukh Idrees, FAST National University, Lhore At: The University of Gujrat, Lahore sub campus, Lahore **MATERIAL DEVELOPMENT** Material Developed for:

Directorate of Staff Development [DSD]. Govt. of the Puniab. Lahore

2011 - IT Teachers for Grade-VIII level [Mathematics]

Directorate of Staff Development [DSD], Govt. of the Punjab, Lahore

2012 - IT Teachers' Training at Secondary level [Physics-ICT]

Directorate of Staff Development [DSD], Govt. of the Punjab, Lahore

2013 - Training Manual Development for Teachers' Training [Gen. Knowledge]

Directorate of Staff Development [DSD], Govt. of the Punjab, Lahore

2013 - Text Book writing for Computer Science, Grade XI and Grade VI

VCAN Publishers, Lahore

2013 - Development of dissemination Charts based on Science Curriculum

Punjab Text Book Board, Lahore

2011 - Test development for Computer Science Classes

Danish School of Excellence, Lahore

2016 - Test preparation Guide for Lecturers through PPSC

Ilmi Kitab Khana, Lahore

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Advisor [Software Engineering Society]

University of Gujrat Lahore Sub Campus, Lahore (Pakistan)

- Chief Executive [Fatima Jinnah Welfare Trust]

University of Gujrat Lahore Sub Campus, Lahore (Pakistan)

REFERENCES

- **Dr. Muhammad Bashir Gondal** Chairman, Department of Education,

University of Gujrat Ph: 0300-4166971 - Prof. Dr. Muzaffar Abbas

Director Campus, University of Gujrat, Lahore campus

Ph: 0300-4455776